dcbbank.com 2013-05-20

# DCB | Privacy & Security

## Development Credit Bank Privacy Policy for Customers

We value your privacy as if it were our own.

Our privacy policy includes information about:

  1. Protecting information about you from marketers outside Development Credit Bank
  2. Making the security of information a priority
  3. Collecting information
  4. Managing information
  5. Making sure information is accurate
  6. Honouring your preferences

This policy covers Customer Information, which means personally identifiable information about a customer or a customer’s current or former relationship with Development Credit Bank.

1\. Protecting Information About You From Marketers Outside Development Credit Bank

Unlike many other financial institutions, Development Credit Bank does not sell or share any Customer Information with marketers outside Development Credit Bank who may want to offer you their own products and services. You don't need to take any action for this benefit.

2\. Making the Security of Information a Priority

Keeping financial information secure is one of our most important responsibilities. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect Customer Information. Employees are authorized to access Customer Information only when they need it to provide you with products and services or to maintain your accounts. Our employees are bound by a code of ethics that requires confidential treatment of Customer Information and are subject to disciplinary action if they fail to follow this code.

3\. Collecting Information

We collect and use various types of information to service your accounts, save you time and money, and better respond to your needs.

Customer Information is categorized in the following five ways:

  1. **Application Information** : information that you provide to us on applications and through other means. Examples include your assets, income and debt. 
  2. **Transaction and Experience Information** : information about your transactions and account experience, as well as information about our communications with you. Examples include your account balances, payment history, parties to transactions, credit card usage, requests for copies of checks and our responses, and pre-approved credit offers. 
  3. **Customer Report Information** : information from a customer report. Examples include your creditworthiness and credit history. 
  4. **Information from Outside Sources** : information from outside sources regarding your employment, credit and other relationships. Examples include your employment history, loan balances, credit card balances, property insurance coverage and other verifications. 
  5. **Other General Information:** information from outside sources, such as data from public records, that is not assembled or used for the purpose of determining your eligibility for a product or service. 

4\. Managing Information

We manage how and when information is shared:

  * Within Development Credit Bank 
  * In other situations 

**Managing information within Development Credit Bank**

We occasionally receive medical or health information from a customer if, for example, a customer applies for insurance from us. We also may obtain information from insurance support organizations not affiliated with Development Credit Bank that prepare and provide reports to others as well as to us. We do not share medical or health information among our companies, except to maintain accounts, process transactions, service customer requests or perform insurance functions, to the extent permitted by law.

**Managing information with companies that work for us**

We may share any of the five categories of Customer Information outlined in this policy with companies that work for us. All companies that act on our behalf are contractually obligated to keep the information we provide to them confidential and to use the Customer Information we share only to provide the services we ask them to perform for you and us. These companies may include financial service providers such as payment processing companies and nonfinancial companies such as check printing and data processing companies. These companies might assist us, for example, in processing your transactions, mailing account statements and fulfilling your service requests.

In addition, we may share any of the five categories of Customer Information with companies that work for us in order to provide marketing support and other services.

**Disclosing information in other situations**

We also may disclose any of the five categories of Customer Information to credit bureaus and similar organizations and when required or permitted by law. For example, Customer Information may be disclosed in connection with a subpoena or similar legal process, and a fraud investigation. Customer Information may also be disclosed to companies that process your requests for products or services, or the sale of your account to another financial institution. We also may share any of the five categories of Customer Information outside Development Credit Bank if we have your consent, such as when you request or when we issue you a credit card associated with an airline frequent flyer program.

You may have other privacy protections under state laws; we will comply with applicable state laws with regard to our information practices.

5\. Making Sure Information is Accurate

Keeping your account information accurate and up to date is very important. You have access to your account information through various means, such as account statements, telephone banking, online banking and in response to specific requests. If your account information is incomplete, inaccurate or not current, please call or write to us at the telephone number or address listed on your account statement, bank records or other documentation. We will promptly update or correct any erroneous information. Please contact us if you have questions or feel that we have not handled information about you properly.

6\. Honoring Your Preferences

You have choices when it comes to how Development Credit Bank shares and uses information.

**Direct Marketing**

You can choose not to receive marketing offers from us by direct mail, telephone and/or e-mail. This preference applies to offers from us about our products and services, and about other products that we think may be of interest to you. To minimize the amount of telephone solicitation our customers receive, Development Credit Bank does not offer nonfinancial products and services through telemarketing.

If you elect not to receive product information by direct mail, telephone or e-mail, you will continue to:

  * Be contacted as necessary to service your account 
  * Be contacted by your relationship manager or assigned account representative, if applicable 
  * Receive marketing information included with your regular account mailings and statements, and when you visit us online or at an ATM 

Since some marketing programs may already be in progress, it may take four to six weeks for your preferences to be fully effective

**Telling us your preferences**

A. Review your preference options.

Direct Marketing

You may request that Development Credit Bank not contact you about direct marketing offers through any or all of the following methods of communication:

  * By mail 
  * By telephone 
  * By e-mail 

Direct marketing offers from Development Credit Bank may include information about new products and services being offered by the bank. If you choose not to hear from us, you may not receive offers about Development Credit Bank products and services that may be of value to you.

B. Tell us your preferences.

You can tell us your preferences by:

  * Talking to a customer representative at a banking center, or to your client relationship manager 
  * When you contact us, please be prepared to provide the following information for each individual: 
    * First name, middle initial and last name  
Address, city, state and pin code  
Telephone number (if applicable)  
E-mail address (if applicable) 

If any of these pieces of information change, please notify us to ensure that your preferences are consistently honored.

Once you have told us your preferences, we will continue to honor them. You do not need to take any further action.

**Guarding your own information**

Development Credit Bank recommends that you take the following precautions to guard against the disclosure and unauthorized use of your account and personal information:

  * Never provide personal information (including account and credit card information) over the phone unless you have initiated the call and know with whom you are speaking 
  * Safeguard ATM, credit and debit cards 
  * Memorize PINs (personal identification numbers) and refrain from writing PINs, credit card numbers where they can easily be found 
  * Immediately change preassigned PINs to a personally memorized PIN 
  * Do not use easily identifiable numbers such as birth dates, addresses, phone numbers or PAN when choosing your PIN 
  * Store cancelled checks, new checks and account statements in a safe place 
  * Tear up or shred unused preapproved credit offers 
  * Report lost or stolen checks, and credit and debit cards immediately 
  * If you have moved within the past year, remember to include your old address and phone number. The same is true for name changes and the addresses and phone numbers associated with each name. 

## Keeping up to date with our Privacy Policy

As required by law, Development Credit Bank will provide notice of our Privacy Policy annually, as long as you maintain an ongoing relationship with us. To receive the most up-to-date Privacy Policy, you can visit our website at: www.dcbl.com/privacy
